ZACHARY SAILE

Front-End Developer

Denver, CO (720) 829-3859 - zwsaile@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/zachary-saile

https://github.com/zwsaile

Frontend Developer with a passion for solving problems and a proven ability to engineer interactive and user-focused web applications. An avid learner who is independent and approachable. Extensive experience working in teams using empathetic and effective communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Developer - S&P Global, Boulder, CO

08/2022 - Present

- Worked on a component team collaborating to build and maintain innovative stock charting solutions for a wide variety of high value clients.
- Utilized an agile workflow to promote continuous integration for many different solutions.

Shelter Manager - Denver Human Services, Denver, CO

01/2020 - 01/2022

- Conducted planning meetings, led collaborative teams with confidence and compassion, and communicated with stakeholders involved in the operation of an emergency response shelter for COVID-19
- Supervised and trained a team of 15 professional staff on policy, health and safety protocols, systems navigation

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design, Denver, CO

01/2022 - 06/2022

- Earned a certificate of completion in the front-end program which focuses on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Held a position on the Student Leadership Committee for a majority of the programs length.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, React, Vue, Express, Git/Github, UX / UI, Cypress, Jest, Jenkins, Jira, Consul, Deployments, SCSS/Sass, Websockets, HTML Canvas, REST APIs

Soft Skills

Leadership, Time Management, Agile Workflow, Verbal Communication, Written Communication

PROJECTS

- Wish You Were Here https://github.com/zwsaile/wish-you-were-here-client
 - An application that allows multiple users to take photos or upload photos and add them to a realtime collaborative whiteboard. The application also features a chat space for the users to send messages to each other
 - Built using React, Web Sockets, Canvas, and Express. Tested with Cypress.io